Caigui Jiang | Curriculum Vitae

Institute of Artificial Intelligence and Robotics - Xi'an Jiaotong University iiang.gr.xjtu.edu.cn

Biography

I am a professor at Institute of Artificial Intelligence and Robotics of Xi' an Jiaotong University in China. Before that, I worked as a research scientist and Postdoc at research scientist at Visual Computing Center (VCC) of King Abdullah University of Science and Technology (KAUST), ICSI, UC Berkeley and the Max Planck Institute for Informatics. I obtained my Ph.D. from KAUST under the supervision of Prof. Dr. Helmut Pottmann and Prof. Dr. Peter Wonka. I received my B.S. and M.S. degrees from Xi' an Jiaotong University (XJTU) in 2008 and 2011 respectively. My research interests are in geometric modeling, geometry processing, architectural geometry, computer graphics, and computer vision.

Education

0	King Abdullah University of Science and Technology	Thuwal, KSA
O	Ph.D in computer science, $GPA - 3.92/4.0$ Supervisors: Prof. Helmut Pottmann & Prof. Peter Wonka	Aug.2011–Jun.2016
0	Xi'an Jiaotong University	Xi'an, China
O	MS in Pattern Recognition and Intelligence Systems, GPA – 88.9/100	Sep.2008–Jul.2011
•	Xi'an Jiaotong University	Xi'an, China
U	BS in Electronic Engineering, GPA - 85.0/100	Sep.2004–Jul.2008

Research Intern

Xi'an Jiaotong University	Xi'an, China
BS in Electronic Engineering, GPA – 85.0/100	Sep.2004–Jul.2008
Experience	
Xi'an Jiaotong University	Xi'an, China
Professor (青拔 A 类)	2021.11-present
King Abdullah University of Science and Technology	Thuwal, KSA
Research Scientist	2019.1–2021.09
ICSI, UC Berkeley	Berkeley, USA
Research Scientist	2018.2–2019.1
Max Planck Institute for Informatics	Saarbrucken, Germany
Postdoc Researcher	2016.8–2018.1
King Abdullah University of Science and Technology	Thuwal, KSA
Research assistant	2011–2016
Microsoft Research Asia	Beijing, China
0	_

Summer, 2015

0	Vienna University of Technology	Vienna, Austria
O	Research Intern	Summer, 2012
0	Xi'an Jiaotong University	Xi'an, China
	Research assistant	2008-2011
F	Publications (ACM SIGGRAPH/SIGGRAPH Asia/TOG)	
0	Planar panels and planar supporting beams in architectural structures	2022
O	ACM Transactions on Graphics (计算机图形顶级期刊,中科院一区,CCF A 类) Caigui Jiang*, Cheng Wang*, Xavier TELLIER, Johannes Wallner, Helmut Pottmann	
0	Using Isometries for Computational Design and Fabrication	2021
O	ACM Transactions on Graphics, SIGGRAPH 2021 (计算机图形顶级期刊,中科院一区,CCF Caigui Jiang, Hui Wang, Victor Ceballos Inza, Florian Rist, Felix Dellinger, Johannes Wallner, Helmut	•
0	Freeform Quad-based Kirigami	2020
O	ACM Transactions on Graphics, SIGGRAPH Asia 2020 (计算机图形顶级期刊,中科院一区,Caigui Jiang, Florian Rist, Johannes Wallner, Helmut Pottmann	CCF A 类)
0	Quad-Mesh Based Isometric Mappings and Developable Surfaces	2020
Ü	ACM Transactions on Graphics, SIGGRAPH 2020 (计算机图形顶级期刊,中科院一区,CCF Caigui Jiang, Cheng Wang, Florian Rist, Johannes Wallner, Helmut Pottmann	⁻ A 类)
0	Curve-pleated Structures	2019
	ACM Transactions on Graphics, SIGGRAPH Asia 2019 (计算机图形顶级期刊,中科院一区, Caigui Jiang, Klara Mundilova, Florian Rist, Johannes Wallner, Helmut Pottmann	CCF A 类)
0	Checkerboard Patterns with Black Rectangles	2019
	ACM Transactions on Graphics, SIGGRAPH Asia 2019(计算机图形顶级期刊,中科院一区,Chi-Han Peng*, Caigui Jiang*, Peter Wonka, Helmut Pottmann (*joint first authors)	CCF A 类)
0	Design and Volume Optimization of Space Structures	2017
O	ACM Transactions on Graphics, SIGGRAPH 2017.(计算机图形顶级期刊,中科院一区,CCF Caigui Jiang, Chengcheng Tang, Hans-Peter Seidel, Peter Wonka	⁻ A 类)
0	Polyhedral Patterns	2015
O	ACM Transactions on Graphics. (计算机图形顶级期刊,中科院一区,CCF A 类, 封面文章) Caigui Jiang, Chengcheng Tang, Amir Vaxmann, Peter Wonka, Helmut Pottmann	
0	Exploring Quadrangulations	2014
U	ACM Transactions on Graphics 33, 1.(计算机图形顶级期刊,中科院一区,CCF A 类) Chi-Han Peng, Michael Barton, Caigui Jiang, and Peter Wonka.	
_	Publications (Others)	
0	Shape-morphing Mechanical Metamaterials	2022
0	Computer-Aided Design, 143, 2022.(计算机辅助设计顶级期刊, CCF B 类) Caigui Jiang, Florian Rist, Hui Wang, Johannes Wallner, Helmut Pottmann	
0	Computational Design of Lightweight Trusses	2021
	Computer-Aided Design, 141, 2021.(计算机辅助设计顶级期刊, CCF B 类) Caigui Jiang, Chengcheng Tang, Hans-Peter Seidel, Renjie Chen, Peter Wonka	

0	Computational design and optimization of quad meshes based on diagonal meshes	2020
O	Advances in Architectural Geometry 2020 Caigui Jiang, Cheng Wang, Eike Schling, Helmut Pottmann	
0	Architectural freeform surfaces designed for cost-effective paneling through mold re-use	2020
O	Advances in Architectural Geometry 2020 Davide Pellis, Martin Kilian, Hui Wang, Caigui Jiang, Christian Muller, Helmut Pottmann	
0	Smooth Polyhedral Surfaces	2020
	Advances in Mathematics, 363, 2020 (数学大类著名期刊,中科院一区, 作者顺序为姓氏首字母顺序) Felix Günther, Caigui Jiang , Helmut Pottmann	
0	Ultimate Force Boundary of Trusses	2019
	IASS Symposium 2019 Caigui Jiang	
0	Field-Aligned Isotropic Surface Remeshing	2018
	Computer Graphics Forum 37, 6. (presented at Eurographics 2018)(计算机图形著名期刊,CCF B 类) Xingyi Du, Xiaohan Liu, Dong-Ming Yan, Caigui Jiang , Juntao Ye, Hui Zhang.	
0	Polyhedral Meshes with Concave Faces	2017
_	SIGGRAPH Asia Posters 2017, Article No. 36. (计算机图形顶级会议) Caigui Jiang, Renjie Chen	
0	Measuring and Controlling Fairness of Triangulations	2016
0	Advances in Architectural Geometry 2016 (Best paper award)(建筑几何会议最佳论文奖) Caigui Jiang, Felix Günther, Johannes Wallner, Helmut Pottmann	
_	Vertex Normals and Face Curvatures of Triangle Meshes	2016
0	In A. I. Bobenko, editor, Advances in Discrete Differential Geometry. Springer Xiang Sun, Caigui Jiang, Johannes Wallner, Helmut Pottmann	
0	Freeform Honeycomb Structures and Lobel Frames	2015
O	SIGGRAPH Posters 2015, Article No. 75.(计算机图形顶级会议) Caigui Jiang, Chengcheng Tang, Jun Wang, Johannes Wallner, Helmut Pottmann	
0	Template Assembly for Detailed Urban Reconstruction	2015
O	Computer Graphics Forum (Proc. Eurographics 2015) 34,2.(计算机图形著名期刊,CCF B 类) Liangliang Nan, Caigui Jiang, Bernard Ghanem, Peter Wonka	
0	Cell Packing Structures	2015
0	Computer-Aided Design 60 (2015), 70-83.(计算机辅助设计顶级期刊,CCF B 类) Helmut Pottmann, Caigui Jiang, Mathias Höbinger, Jun Wang, Philippe Bompas, Johannes Wallner.	
0	Interactive Modeling of Architectural Freeform Structures	2014
O	Advances in Architectural Geometry 2014, London, UK. Caigui Jiang, Chengcheng Tang, Marko Tomicic, Johannes Wallner, Helmut Pottmann.	
0	Freeform Honeycomb Structures	2014
	Computer Graphics Forum (Proc. SGP 2014) 33,5.(计算机图形著名期刊,CCF B 类) Caigui Jiang, Jun Wang, Johannes Wallner, Helmut Pottmann.	
0	Freeform Shading and Lighting Systems from Planar Quads	2013
	Design Modelling Symposium Berlin 2013, Germany.	

Caigui Jiang, Jun Wang, Philippe Bompas, Johannes Wallner, Helmut Pottmann.

Discrete Line Congruences for Shading and Lighting

2013

Computer Graphics Forum (Proc. SGP 2013) 32,5.(计算机图形著名期刊, CCF B 类) Jun Wang, Caigui Jiang, Philippe Bompas, Johannes Wallner, Helmut Pottmann.

Selected Talks

0	Curved-pleated Structures	Brisbane, Australia
	SIGGRAPH Asia 2019	Nov. 2019
0	Design and Volume Optimization of Space Structures	LA, USA
	SIGGRAPH 2017	Aug. 2017
0	Geometric Rationalization for Free-from Architecture	MPII, Germany
	invited by Prof. Hans-Peter Seidel & Dr. Renjie Chen	Mar. 2016
0	Polyhedral Patterns	Kobe, Japan
O	SIGGRAPH Asia 2015	Nov. 2015
	Geometric Rationalization for Free-from Architecture	EPFL, Switzerland
0	invited by Prof. Mark Pauly	Apr. 2015
	Interactive Modeling of Architectural Freeform Structures	London, UK
O	Advances in Architectural Geometry 2014	Oct. 2014
0	Freeform Honeycomb Structures	Cardiff, UK
O	SGP 2014	Jul. 2014
0	Hexagonal torsion-free structures	Paris, France
0	Curves and Surfaces 2014	Jun. 2014
0	Discrete Line Congruences for Shading and Lighting	Berlin, Germany
	Design Modelling Symposium 2013	Oct. 2013

Awards

• Best Paper Award: Advances in Architectural Geometry 2016

Skills

- **Programming**: C/C++, Matlab, Pov-Ray, Rhino script, LATEX
- o API: OpenGL, OpenMesh, OpenCV, Qt
- Software Tools: Modeling: Rhinoceros, 3ds Max. Rendering: Pov-Ray, Keyshot, V-ray.
- Language: Chinese (native), English

Professional Activities

- Membership: ACM, IEEE, IASS
- o Reviewer: SIGGRAPH, SIGGRAPH Asia, SPM, CAD, IEEE CGA, Computer & Graphics, Graphical Models
- International Program Committee: GMP 2021, CAD/Graphics 2021